Preliminary Inventory of the Council for Basic Education records
Hoover Institution Archives
Council for Basic Education records
1956-2004
2009C29
Council for Basic Education.
66 manuscript boxes (24.6 linear feet)
Hoover Institution Archives Stanford, California 94305-6010
Materials relating to education in the United States including minutes, correspondence, reports, proposals, studies, memoranda, financial records, bulletins, press releases, other issuances, and printed matter.
Administrative Information
Access
Collection is open for research.
Access to sound recordings, video recordings, or motion picture material requires at least two weeks advance notice. Please contact the Hoover Institution Archives for further information.
Acquisition Information
Acquired by the Hoover Institution Archives.
Accruals
Materials may have been added to the collection since this finding aid was prepared. To determine if this has occurred, find the collection in Stanford University's online catalog Socrates at http://library.stanford.edu/webcat. Materials have been added to the collection if the number of boxes listed in Socrates is larger than the number of boxes listed in this finding aid.
Related Materials
Basic Education, 1979-2003. Stanford University Libraries
Bulletin. Council on Basic Education (or CBE Bulletin) 1956-1979, Stanford University Libraries
Biographical/Historical Note
A private, nonprofit American organization for promotion of education
Scope and Content of Collection
Materials relating to education in the United States including minutes, correspondence, reports, proposals, studies, memoranda, financial records, bulletins, press releases, other issuances, and printed matter.
Indexing Terms
The following terms have been used to index the description of this collection in the library's online public access catalog.
Education--United States.
Collection Contents
- Development files, A-K (Folder 2-5)
- Development files, L-NESA (Folder 14-17)
- Development files, Nev-V (Folder 10-12)
- Development files, W and miscellaneous (Folder 53-56)
- Development files, miscellaneous (Folder 6-9, 23-25, 63-66)
- Board meeting materials, 1981-1992 (Folder 32-33)
- Board meeting materials, 1993-1999 (Folder 57-59)
- Board meeting materials, 2000-2004 (Folder 60-62)
- Archives, NEH, 1997 (Folder 18-20)
- Archives, 1996-2001 (Folder 36-38)
- Principal Leadership Academy, 2000-2004 (Folder 39-41)
- District of Columbia Public Schools, 2000-2004 (Folder 39-41)
- Occasional papers, 1961-1984 (Folder 26-28)
- Charter Fellowships, 1999-2000 (Folder 42-44)
- District of Columbia Public Schools, circa 2000-2001 (Folder 42-44)
- Mid-Atlantic Regional Teachers Project, 1999-2002 (Folder 42-44)
- Annual Reports, 1961-2000 (Folder 48-52)
- Closing the Gap, 2000 (Folder 48-52)
- Great Expectations, 1998 (Folder 48-52)
- Certificate of Incorporation and Bylaws (Folder 48-52)
- Better Teachers, 1988 (Folder 48-52)
- Dissertations (Folder 21-22)
- CBE Bulletins (Folder 13, 29-31)
- Books (Folder 1, 45-47)
- Reports, membership information, meetings, 1975 (Folder 34-35)
- Files and correspondence, 1960-1970s, 1992-1994 (Folder 34-35)